Nilesh BirariFeatured Resume

MCTS Senior Software Developer seeking roles in Application
Development, Programming, Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution
Designing, Office 365, Share Point, SPFX, ASP. NET, C#, . Net
Rest, Ajax, Java Script, Jquery, XML, HTML, CSS, TFS.

Current Designation: Senior Software Developer - SharePoint

Current Company: Ocwen

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Pune, Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Key Skills: Senior Software Developer, Tech Lead, Application
Development, Programming, Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution
Designing, Office 365, SharePoint, SPFX, ASP. NET, C#, . Net
Framework, Ajax, JavaScript, Jquery, XML, HTML, CSS, TFS, Node. Js, SQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

ID: 17c657f44b6c29bb69Last Active: 17-Sep-20Last Modified: 17-Sep-20

Jump to SectionWork Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Presently associated with Ocwen, Pune as Senior Software Developer

Total 9 years of competitive experience in IT industry using Microsoft Technology (SharePoint, SharePoint Online, Office 365, ASP.NET, C#, Power Apps and Power Automate (Flow)).

Basic knowledge for Azure cloud technology.

Acquired International Certificate Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) in Asp.net 3.5 application development.

Experience of working in the complete Software development life cycle involving development, testing and maintenance.

Worked as a Faculty for SharePoint training for Ocwen.

Worked as a Panelist for the interviews for Ocwen.

Good work ethics with excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

Expertise in Understanding User Requirements and preparing Functional and Technical Specification documents.

Have received appreciation from each Client for individual talent, commitment, extensive technical knowledge and leadership shown in development and implementation of project.

Work Experience

Ocwen as Senior Software Developer - SharePoint

Apr 2016 to Till Date

Project: #1 (Migration Project Online)

Employer: Ocwen

Title (Designation): Senior SharePoint Developer

Project: PHH to Ocwen Tenant SharePoint O365 to O365 Site Migration

Software: O365, SharePoint Designer 2013, InfoPath, Power Apps, Power Automate(Flow),

ShareGate Tool

Client: In House

Description: Ocwen takeover PHH overall 30 phh SharePoint site are migrated to Ocwen tenant with the help of ShareGate tool overall around 900GB data size and site are in production environment so without business impact activity successfully perform

Roles and Responsibility:

Migrate one tenant SharePoint site to another tenant.

Doing POC before and after migration.

Identify risk factors while doing migration.

Making documentation and taking call with project manager and provide inputs.

After Migration users facing issue related form workflow permission resolve on priority.

Doing plan and strategy for utilization of resources.

Project: #2 (Migration Project On-Prem to Cloud)

Employer: Ocwen

Title (Designation): Senior SharePoint Developer

Project: SharePoint 2010 to Cloud O365 Site Migration

Software: SharePoint 2013, SharePoint Designer 2013, InfoPath Designer 2013, Power Automate

(Flow), Power Apps, Jquery.

Client: In House

Description: In Altisource environment we have 75 SharePoint sites which we have migrated in new O365 environment and move in Ocwen environment with the help of Metalogix and ShareGate tool, we have achieved this task with in time line also this site have any permission, web part, workflow issue we have resolve instantly as well as user having new requirement also work accordingly.

I have worked on InfoPath forms, Web parts and workflows for sending notification emails.

Resolving service now tickets.

Roles and Responsibility:

Migrate SharePoint 2010 site in o365 cloud environment also migrate custom web part and lists workflows.

Working on Service now tickets as per user requirement co-ordinate with user understand the requirement and work accordingly with in SLA.

Develop and design list-based InfoPath forms in InfoPath designer 2013

Mphasis as Delv Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2015 to Apr 2016

Employer: Mphasis

Title (Designation): SharePoint Developer

Project: JPPL

Software: SharePoint 2013 SharePoint Designer 2013, office 365, JQuery.

Client : Jet Privilege

Description: Jet Privilege Private Limited is a specialized loyalty and rewards management company - a JV between Jet Airways and Etihad Airways to develop, manage, operate and market the Jet Privilege? an internationally acclaimed, award winning loyalty and rewards program.

Jet Privilege the proud recipient of the prestigious Freddie Awards in 2012 and 2013 will continue to be a Frequent Flyer and rewards program with Jet Airways as its key anchor partner - offering exclusive privileges to members when they travel on Jet Airways, Etihad Airways and its tie-ups with other international airlines. The program offers unique benefit of accelerating JP-Miles accumulation through use of co-branded credit and debit cards, book & stay across domestic and international hotel partners, and various other partnerships with other leading consumer and retail brands across industries like retail, telecom, lifestyle, dining, entertainment to name a few.

Roles and Responsibility:

Developing List & Library as per the business & application logic for the modules.

Creating Views and write Jquery for client side doing operation.

Interact with client & gathering requirement & develop accordingly.

Trigyn as Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2014 to Jun 2015

Project: #4 (International Organization and Migration (IOM))

Employer: Trigyn Technologies

Title (Designation): SharePoint Developer, Support

Project: International Organization and Migration (IOM)

Software: SharePoint 2013 SharePoint Designer 2013, Jquery.

Client: IOM (Switzerland)

Description: IOM-PRIMA is IDF's (IOM Development Fund?s) fund management system application, which manages the business processes involved in funding for migration projects or emergencies. It consists of various business process workflows and approval levels which helps IOM in evaluating the details of the project, the cost factor, beneficiaries, donors etc. It also provides monitoring & reporting of the projects after it has been funded, so that the organization has a clear glimpse of the activities and the fund utilization.

Roles and Responsibility:

Developing web-parts screens and business & application logic for the modules.

Triggers or crucial event receivers for the project.

Developing the underlying data storage structure (Content types & lists) for the entire application.

Communicating with the client regarding the requirements

Analysis of the business requirements and discussing with client the best approach of doing it.

Deployment of the application at the client side.

Maintenance activities of the project

Datamatics HR & Consultancy PVT. LTD. as SharePoint Developer

Oct 2013 to Sep 2014

Project: #5 (MasteknetPortal)

Employer: Datamatics HR & Consultancy PVT. LTD.

Title (Designation): SharePoint Developer, Support.

Project: MasteknetPortal

Software: SharePoint 2013 SharePoint Designer 2013, Jquery.

Client: Mastek

Description: An interactive web application developed using SharePoint 2010. It keeps track of daily work.

It is a Publishing Site with windows authentication. It Implements almost all Out of Box components of SharePoint 2010.

Roles & Responsibility:

- * Migration from SharePoint 2010 to SharePoint server 2013.
- * Involved in Cookie based authentication with ASP.net Intranet application.
- * Created different types of Groups and users who have different access roles on the portal.
- * Involved in the Analyzing, Designing user interface and Coding.

Search Applications:

- * Configured advanced search with new features like Refinement panel, best beats, federated search.
- * Configured search suggestion.
- * Created and configured various scopes.
- * Implemented Managed Metadata and Taxonomy Refinements.
- * Configured People Search with custom user properties.
- * Implemented My Sites.

- * Configured PDF indexing to crawled contents of the PDF file.
- * Configured audiences to control and manage different areas of Application.

Customizations:

- * Developed weekly and daily SharePoint job.
- * Involved in developing list Definitions, sub sites.
- * Involved in developing User controls.

Project: #6 (Knithub Portal)

Employer: Datamatics HR & Consultancy PVT. LTD.

Title (Designation): SharePoint Developer, Support.

Project: Knithub Portal

Software: SharePoint 2013 SharePoint Designer 2013, JQuery.

Client: Mastek

Description: An interactive web application developed using SharePoint 2010 .It is Document Management system. It is a Publishing Site with windows authentication. Users above the certain grade can create their own sub sites using custom templates to maintain documents. Portal has different community Site collections own by the group heads. It Implements almost all Out of Box components of SharePoint 2010.

Roles and Responsibility:

- * Migration from SharePoint 2010 to SharePoint server 2013.
- * Created different types of Groups and users who have different access roles Onthe portal.
- * Involved in the Analyzing, Designing user interface and Coding.
- * Providing support on using various features of SharePoint to clients.

Search Applications:

- * Configured advanced search with new features like Refinement panel, best beats, federated search.
- * Configured search suggestion.
- * Created and configured various scopes.
- * Implemented Managed Metadata and Taxonomy Refinements.
- * Configured People Search with custom user properties.
- * Implemented My Sites.
- * Configured PDF indexing to crawled contents of the PDF file.

* Configured audiences to control and manage different areas of Application.

Customizations:

- * Developed weekly and daily SharePoint job.
- * Involved in developing list Definitions, sub sites.
- * Involved in developing User controls.
- * Implemented Custom Site Definitions and templates so that end users can create
- * Subsides to maintain Project related documents.

Syntel as Software Engineer

Dec 2010 to May 2013

Project: #7 (Allstate Insur, Prism Support)

Employer: Syntel LTD

Title (Designation): SharePoint Developer

Project: Allstate Insur, Prism Support.

Software/Tech: SharePoint 2010, SharePoint Designer 2010, JavaScript.

Client : Allstate

Description: The Allstate Corporation is the largest publicly held personal lines property and casualty insurer in America. Allstate was founded in 1931 and became a publicly traded company in 1993. All State listed on the New York Stock Exchange under the trading symbol ALL. Allstate is widely known through the "You're In Good Hands With Allstate ®" slogan. All state insures support site developed in SharePoint 2010 it maintains the information according to module.

Roles and Responsibility:

- * Development and enhancement of Nintex Workflows.
- * Developed Nintex workflows.
- * Creation and Deployment of solutions on production server and testing the same.
- * Requirement capturing, analysis, design, and documentation.
- * Interacting with client to understand the problem statements.
- * Preparation of the functional specification document, and design documents.

Project: #8 (Admin Portal)

Employer: Syntel LTD

Title (Designation): SharePoint Developer

Project: Admin Portal

Software/Tech: Visual Studio 2010, SharePoint 2010, SharePoint Designer 2010

Client: In House

Description: In that project there are various modules like access card business card Gate pass request, mobile request and cab request like that when the requester raised request it send mail by using workflow.

Roles and Responsibility:

- * Worked on calendar list, programming on calendar list, developed various views.
- * Developing web part which allows user to book the rooms and validation with JQuery.
- * Branding master page.
- * Developed supportive features and event receiver to send outlook meeting.
- * Deployment, backup of application, Unit testing and defect tracking.

Project: #9 (ECCO)

Employer: Syntel LTD

Title (Designation): SharePoint Developer

Project: ECCO

Software/Tech: Aprimo tool Kit, Visual Studio 2010,

Client: Amex

Description: American Stock Exchange. The second-largest stock exchange in the U.S., after the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE). In general, the listing rules are a little more lenient than those of the NYSE, and thus the AMEX has a larger representation of stocks and bonds issued by smaller companies than the NYSE. In ECCO module create the offers for the various type of cards like gold, platinum & silver.

Roles and Responsibility:

- * Understand the ECCO K245.
- * Preparing ECCO Design Documents for the Requirements.
- * Implementing the logic into the application as per the given requirements.
- ^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Chemistry) from Pune University in 2006

PG: MCA (Computers) from University of Pune, Pune in 2009

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

ASP.NET, C# 2015 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

JavaScript 2019 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Power Shell 2019 3 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

MS SQL SERVER 2000 2014 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

WEB SERVER 2016 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Sharepoint 2010 2019 5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Nintex Workflow, Office 365 2020 4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

Ajax, Jquery 2020 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

XML, HTML, CSS, REST 2020 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

sharepoint designer 2010/2013 2020 7 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Visual studio 2005, 2008R2 2016 3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

TFS 2016 3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

SNOW, ITSM 2020 4 Year(s) 3 Month(s)

AZURE 2020 0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language Proficiency Read Write Speak

English Expert

Marathi